Garrett Howard

American Fork UT, 84003

Phone: (801) 592-0371

Email: hylander.garrett@gmail.com **Personal:** https://ghoward.dev/

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/garrett-howard-859007a0/

Github: https://github.com/meta-byte

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER & IT SUPPORT SPECIALIST

Full-Stack Web Developer with a background in IT support. Certificate from University of Utah Professional Education program in full stack web technologies. A self starter with a passion for problem solving and creating responsive web applications. IT experience allows me to perceive potential problems faced by end users, making me a strong addition to any development team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages and Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, Express.js, React.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Git, Command Line

Certifications: CompTIA Project+, CompTIA A+, CIW Advanced HTML5 and CSS3, CIW Site Development

Other Skills: G-Suite, Microsoft Office 365, Computer system repair, Installation of operating systems,

Hardware and software troubleshooting, Proficient in Japanese

PROJECTS

React Directory

Tech Used: React.js Materialize Heroku

First ever react app. The focus was to display a list of end users in a sortable and filterable format while

updating the page using "state".

Live: https://bit.ly/2LSXXMI | Github: https://bit.ly/2ATun7u

Earthquake Tracker

Tech Used: React.js, USGS Earthquake API, Google Maps API, Auth0, Bootstrap, Heroku

An application that lets users search earthquakes near a latitude and longitude. Users are authenticated with Auth0 and the last performed search is saved so it is presented to the user on next login.

Live: https://bit.ly/2WRPi3c | Github: https://bit.ly/2zmf5HV

Ski Resort Weather

Tech Used: jQuery, Google Maps API, Twitter API, Weather Unlocked API, Materialize, Github pages A web application that allows users to look at weather and snow conditions at a given resort. The app displays a map with a location to the resort and a twitter feed from the resort.

Live: https://bit.ly/3bTMVBh | Github: https://bit.ly/3gaJpWJ

EXPERIENCE

Canopy - IT Support Specialist September 2019 - Present

Lehi, UT

Dedicated IT support technician for needs within the Canopy office. Troubleshooting of hardware, software and network issues. Inventory equipment and replace as needed. Create documentation for IT policies and current infrastructure configurations. Provisioning and deprovisioning of resources for Canopy employees. Other projects as needed by the DevOps team.

• Recommended and implemented a new MDM solution to provide a better experience to users and allow for easier tracking of Mac devices.

Dell EMC - Technical Support Engineer Level I

August 2017 - June 2018

Draper, UT

Member of the Dell EMC Recoverpoint product team. Completed Information Storage and Management v3 certification. Completed Dell EMC Recoverpoint product certification. Worked with end users to troubleshoot data protection and recovery systems. Provided end users with Dell EMC recommended storage procedures. Frequent system log analysis. Troubleshooting of both physical and virtual storage environments. Dispatch field technicians to replace or re-install components in customer environments.

Revere Health- IT Service Desk Analyst Level II May 2015 - June 2017

Provo, UT

Support of end users in both software and hardware. Take support phone calls and dispatch analysts to on site locations. Creation of support tickets for the tracking of incidents and follow up. Troubleshooting of hardware and software. Replace or repair broken computer components. Imaging and placement of new computer systems and equipment. Time as an "on call" analyst working after hours. Understanding of DNS, DHCP and basic network infrastructure.

• Helped implement a new support model to better help staff in remote office locations.

EDUCATION

Western Governors University - Software Development

October 2018 - December 2020

• 68 credit hours completed towards a Bachelor of Science in Software Development.

University of Utah - Full-Stack Web Development

November 2019 - May 2020

Professional Education Certificate of Completion